Guide to the Aaron Rabinowitz/Fred F. French collection, 1938-2004.
Rabinowitz, Aaron/Fred F. French collection, 1938-2004
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Aaron Rabinowitz/Fred F. French collection, 1938-2004.
4264
Aaron Rabinowitz, 1884-1973.
1 cubic ft.
Records, correspondence, clippings, photographs, papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence and real estate records relating to the sale of property at 250 Church Street, 42 Broadway and the "White Block" in New York City.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Real estate developer.
In 1903, he founded a real estate business in New York City, served on the New York State Board of Housing since 1926, become condemnation commissioner for the Port of New York Authority in 1932, was appointed as advisor to the New York State Insurance Commissioner, and served as trustee for bonds issued by the New York Title and Mortgage Company from 1935 to 1953. In 1937, he became chairman of the Fred F. French Investing Company, which owned business and residential properties in New York City.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Real estate records relating to the sale of property at 250 Church Street, 42 Broadway and the "White Block" in New York City, including correspondence, clippings, photographs, legal papers, and financial papers, 1948-1959. Also, publications and miscellany relating to the Insurance Advisory Board, 1938-1939. Annual financial reports of the Fred F. French Investing Company, Inc., 1928-1980. Writings on Aaron Rabinowitz and Fred F. French, including two centennial biographies by Alan Rabinowitz; a 1942 Bishop's Service confidential report on the Fred F. French Investing Co.; and "So Long Avalon - or - Farewell F-1," a report by Stephen Thompson abou the wind-up in 1952 of the F-1 Series Trust. Source documents on Aaron Rabinowitz's activities, 1884-1973 including a "Background Note" by Alan Rabinowitz, 2004; documents relating the the induction of Lillian D. Wald's induction into the Hall of Fame for Great Americans at NYU; a set of the "Spear and Company Bulletin: A Journal for Realty Owners," 1913-1914. Source documents on Fred F. French and his activities include a "Financial History, 1928-1980 of the Fred F. French Investing Company," compiled by Alan Rabinowitz, 1989; copies of all of the annual financial reports of the FFF Investing Co.; a microfilm of important documents relating to various law suits by disaffected stockholders; and a copy of the 11th edition of "The French Plan," 1929; as well as a variety of articles about Fred F. French and his various enterprises. Also materials about Tudor City and other Fred F. French Companies properties including "Tudor City Historic District" Landmarks Preservation Commission report; "Financial History of Tudor City, New York, 1930-1968," by Alan Rabinowitz, 1988; final opinion by the Court of Appeals on a rezoning law suit; and miscellaneous materials about other properties.
Also, "The Life and Times of Aaron Rabinowitz," by Susan Rabinowitz Malloy, published in 2004 by the American Jewish Archives.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Rabinowitz, Aaron, 1884-1973.; Levy, Samuel.; Noyes, Charles F.; Rifkind, Simon R.; Rosenblatt, Samson.; Cardiff Corporation.; Fred F. French Investing Company.; New York (State). Insurance Advisory Board.
Subjects:
Real property, Exchange of--New York (State)--New York.; Real estate business--New York (State)--New York.; Real estate development--New York (State)--New York.; Corporations--Real estate investments.; Real estate developers.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Insurance Advisory Board, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Insurance Advisory Board Publication, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Insurance Advisory Board - Lewis H. Pink Publications, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 250 Church Special File, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
  Correspondence discussing possible "Sale of the Property," which took place between Nov. 1952 and 1953
- 250 Church St. (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
  Construction Progress; Leasing Problems; Mortgage Consideration
  Correspondence between Charles F. Noyes, Samuel Levy, Aaron Rabinowitz, Samson Rosenblatt
- 250 Church St. Realty Inc., 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
- 250 Church St. - Clippings, Photographs, etc. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- 250 Church St. (Box 1, Folder 13-17)
  Organizational Correspondence; Purchase of Property at Auction; Agreement between The Group; Closing Statements; Formation of the New Corporation; Letters re contributions to the venture; Dissolution of Corporation; 1949 Special Tax Correspondence; 1949 Dr. Dublin National Health Council; 1949 State Insurance Fund
- 250 Church St., 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 18-22)
- The White Block - Clippings, Photographs, Maps, etc. (Box 1, Folder 23-24)
- The "White Block" Hospital Properties (Box 1, Folder 25-29)
- Broadway - Organizational Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 30-33)
  Organizational Correspondence; Purchase of the Property; Agreements between The Group; Closing Statements
- 42 Broadway - Clippings, Press Releases, Photographs, etc. (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Correspondence, A.R. with Fred F. French Investing Co., re 250 Church St., The White Block, 42 Broadway (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Correspondence, A.R. with the Cardiff Corporation, re 250 Church St., The White Block, 42 Broadway (Box 1, Folder 36)
- 250 Church St. - Regular Routine Correspondence, 1953; 1955,; 1959 (Box 1, Folder 37-38)
- Correspondence, A.R. with Judge Simon R. Rifkind, re 250 Church St., The White Block, 42 Broadway (Box 1, Folder 39)
- A Last Word on Aaron Rabinowitz (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Financial History of Tudor City (Box 1, Folder 41)
- The Life and Times of Aaron Rabinowitz (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Fred F. French Investing Company, Inc.: Financial Reports (copies), 1928-1946 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Fred F. French Investing Company, Inc.: Financial Reports (copies), 1947-1961 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Fred F. French Investing Company, Inc.: Financial Reports (copies), 1962-1968 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Fred F. French Investing Company, Inc.: Financial Reports (copies), 1969-1975 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Fred F. French Investing Company, Inc.: Financial Reports (copies), 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 47)